ELISIA WRIGHT



wrighte@allegheny.edu github.com/ElisiaW



+1 (609) 630-3178



232 Rivers Farm Road West Burke, VT 05871 Named one of the top 60 undergraduate researchers in the United States.

My research and passion is helping to find practical solutions for environmental challenges through computational sustainability.

Avid PC builder, gamer and modder captivated by the connection between hardware and software components.

EDUCATION

Allegheny College, Meadville, PA Cumulative GPA: 3.38/4.00 Expected Graduation: 05/2021

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science,

Environmental Studies

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, C++, C
- Git, Netlify, Travis Cl, Gatsby, Jekyll, Bootstrap, React, Docker

RECOGNITIONS

- One of the top 60 undergraduate researchers in the United States (Posters on the Hill 2019)
- Outstanding Achievement in Research Award (The Council on Undergraduate Research)
- Research has been featured in: The Washington Times, USA Today, Environmental Monitor Magazine, Allegheny Magazine, Erie-Times News
- PERC Campus Sustainability Champion for 2020
- Black Excellence Award (Association for the Advancement of Black Culture)

ACTIVITIES

- Founding charter member and Parliamentarian of the Pi Phi Chapter of Zeta Phi Beta Sorority, Inc.
- Volunteer Judge at Pennsylvania Junior Academy of Science
- **Social Media Chair** of the Green Students of Color Society
- Member of Computer Building Club

WORK EXPERIENCE

Allegheny Mozilla Fellow – Allegheny College

08/2019 - Present

- Lead website developer
- Engineer tools and programs that integrate ethics into core curriculum
- TextMining research accepted to: PyCon 2020 (canceled due to COVID-19)

Computer Science Technical Leader - Allegheny College

08/2019 - Present

- Assist in class and laboratory sessions with instructional responsibilities
- Hold office hours to effectively troubleshoot and resolve technical issues

Environmental Research Assistant – Allegheny College

09/2018 - Present

 Assist in the lab and field with long-term experiments related to climate change and acid rain

Undergraduate Research Fellow – Allegheny College

05/2019 - 08/2019

Conducted independent research under guidance of faculty advisor

Additional Work Experience Available Upon Request

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Senior Thesis: Improving Industrial Hemp Cultivation Techniques with a Web Application

12/2019 - Present

Develop user-based app for farmers to increase total harvest of hemp

An Intelligent Underwater Robotic Smart-Sensing System for Water Quality Testing

09/2018 - Present

- Engineered robot for predicting and analyzing water quality trends
- Presented at: The United States Congress (<u>Posters on the Hill 2019</u>) and The 32nd International Conference of the Florida Artificial Intelligence Research Society (<u>FLAIRS-32</u>)

Using Python and GitHub for Team Formation and Assessment

01/2019 - 05/2019

- Project supervisor of GatorGrouper web application development
- Presented at: PyCon 2019